Right. I considered fixing my hair, but
I think I think it'll just be funnier
um
if
if we if we just do it like this.
All right, guys. Welcome to 100 FX the
most woke trading channel on YouTube
here. Today, we're going to
uh do a tier list of the uh the best
indicators and the worst indicators.
Now, if it was up to me, you guys know
it already. All the indicators would be
[__] There's some that are better than
others and there's some that I can
actually make you a little bit profit.
Some can actually help you understand
some things a little bit here. Um so,
let's do a fun quick video of the tier
list of the different indicators that
you could be using as a Forex trader.
This is specifically Forex trading. Um
let's dive into them.
[Music]
Uh what we've done is we've loaded up 10
indicators and you're probably wondering
what the hell are these. Uh they're just
some pretty little images uh that I
found on the internet and I wonder if
you can figure them out before I
actually tell you what they are. So,
what we're going to do is we're going to
go one by one uh and we're going to see
uh where things all lie out. Let's start
off
with the simple one here. Um moving
averages. I've just put it on Adobe
Spark here some something like this.
It's a little bit easier for us here to
to manage. Um moving average guys,
moving average if we look at the chart
here. Uh looking at the moving averages
on the chart here, you can see um using
a moving average as some sort of trend
continuation uh a sort of trend um
bias figuring out the bias of what the
trend is going to be is going to be
pretty good with a moving average. Um
it's going to tell you on the higher
time frame okay, if we're above the
moving average, uh it might be a good
time to be looking for buys on the lower
time frame. Uh but when it's going
sideways, it's really really choppy. So,
it doesn't always work. So, we're going
to put the moving average as a rough C
tier starting off right around in the
middle where it's got a use, but it's
not all that useful. So, let's look at
the next one. Let's just look at volume.
Obviously, you guys know the volume of
the square. We can use volume to
determine how much uh pressure is going
into a level. Uh if there's a lot of
volume breaking out of a level, it might
be useful in determining uh that it
actually is a true breakout. Uh we can
also use uh volume as a the volume
profile as well. So, we can see what
range uh has the most volume, uh what
levels are creating the most volume
rather. Uh and then also we can use
volume on this side to say, "Hey, uh you
know, there's a lot of volume here. Uh
so, most likely this is going to
actually be breaking out when we are
breaking this level." So, I think we can
put volume as a bit more a bit more
useful than a moving average and we'll
put it at maybe a
a a B, I think because
uh this way the volume is actually quite
helpful in seeing how much pressure is
in the market, um but it's not good at
trading itself. It can't give you any
entries. It can't tell you the bias. It
can't do anything other than tell you
how many people are trading at that
time. All right, jumping to another
random one here, guys. If you are
familiar with this image, it says MACD.
So, if you guys remember from long ago
uh in the streams, I had drawn out MACD
uh and if you are a a a veteran in the
channel here, uh then you'll you will
recognize this and I don't remember what
day I drew it there, but it's way back
way back on the live streams here. So, I
think MACD is a a really crappy
indicator. Let's type in MACD here. It
is a very very lagging indicator. It
doesn't really add to much confluence
and the only thing that you can really
use it for is divergences. So, we're
going to drop the
MACD all the way down to
a E tier because it can be used in
divergences, but it's not very good at
all. It's kind of the crappy the crappy
little brother of indicators uh that
always [__] things up for you. So,
we've added the RSI here a relative
strength index. Obviously, you can tell
here guys uh the relative strength
index, it is a much much much better uh
indicator in terms of um
divergences. It will actually make you
some money uh if you are new. And let's
type in RSI here and let's just see some
divergence here. A divergence happening
right here. Yeah, so you can see it
increasing, but this is decreasing and
then there's a reversal. So, it doesn't
give you any targets. It doesn't give
you any stop losses, but it can tell you
roughly when the trend is going to be
changing and we don't know to how how
much degree or anything like that. It's
a really really great indicator when it
does come to indicators, right? So,
we're actually going to place this guy I
think all the way up at the A tier here.
He's going to be a really really strong
competitor. He's going to be one of the
best indicators. He's very easy to use
and he can make you money just using it.
Pretty much that and the candlesticks
and the price action. Moving on, let's
look at This is an airplane. It is an
ATR average true range. It is a type of
airplane as well. Um so, the ATR simply
is used for um how far your stops are
maybe going to be placed. It's for the
true range. How how wide is the usual
price uh being moved around. So, a
higher ATR is uh you you can say that
this is the average amount of pips that
the price moves. So, right around here,
we're getting a much much more of um a
much wider range of of the volatility.
So, we're going to be wanting a wider
stop here. That's all the ATR is pretty
much used for is where you're going to
be putting your stop. And sometimes
people use um
arbitrary stop not arbitrary stop, but
kind of a random stop placement based
off of the ATR. So, that's not based off
price action so that it's not obvious
where your stops are so the market
makers can't really hunt you. So, uh
ATR, it's
okay in a aiding sense, but you don't
need it in any sense.
Uh it can it can help you if you want to
put a random stop. It's a very rare
situation. So, we're going to put this
in a
in a lower class. We're going to put
this right around a I think a D tier
here an ATR. Um and it's just not not
very useful, but some people might be
able to find use in it. Moving on here,
guys, we have another one. This guy is
the king. This guy is required by
everyone and it can be used alone,
right? This one if you trade price
action alone, you can be very very
profitable. And this is what I
specifically do. Um so, obviously, I'm
going to be biased, uh but it is
required with every trading strategy.
So, this is why this is the ultimate S
tier. There is no question about it.
This guy will blow everything out of the
water and it's required no matter what.
Looking at something more candle
related, let's look at uh candlestick
patterns. This is just specific patterns
um you know, hammers uh you know, the
the triple white knights or whatever uh
the dojis things like this. This is
going to go hand in hand with basically
a moving average, right? Because that's
exactly what we used a moving average
for. It's just going to be trend
following. It's going to be useful on
the higher time frame, but not very
useful in the rest of the trading. Next
one, it is parabolic SAR. Parabolic SAR,
it's another stop out indicator. So, you
know, if you were to get into a long
here, you would just move your stop
along uh and then once it once it got to
your your star there, then you'd stop
out here, right? Um so, it is a good
tool for knowing if you're not very good
at placing your stop and if you want to
trail your own stop, um then it could be
useful for you, but it is not very
useful on its own. It doesn't give you
targets. It doesn't give you entries.
So, this is another one where it's going
to be actually a lower tier um and I'm
going to put it
with MACD here. It's going to be quite
quite useless. Fibonacci guys, this is a
this is a good one. You guys have seen
me use Fibonacci. Um let's just draw a
Fibonacci out here.
It's going to be used for retracements.
You know, you can come you can come back
down to this kind of golden area
and look for trend changes around that
area. So, it's going to be a great
useful, it's going to be something uh
that we're going to have to use with
something else. So, we're actually going
to put it at a A tier um because it is
one of the best ones. I would say it's
on par with RSR. Getting close to the
end here, Bollinger Bands. Bollinger
Bands guys, let's look at it. Let's
clear this up again. Let's go Bollinger.
Bollinger Bands really just kind of
shows you where things could be bouncing
getting to extremes. I've tested a lot.
It doesn't do anything really, guys.
This is a crappy crappy one. I think
some of the this theory is after it
comes back in the range, but it can
still keep coming back out. And I've
tested multiple multiple different
theories and it never seems to be
consistent with anything. So, it might
be useful in conjunction with other
things, but it's safe to say that this
is one of the worst indicators that you
can have in the top of indicators.
Moving on, last one here, guys, Ichimoku
Cloud. Of course, the only thing that's
named after a cloud. So, Ichimoku Cloud
is a good trend following system, right?
Its idea is that it's um very confusing
is the first idea um is that 80% of
profit is taken within the trend. So, as
long as you're just trading that trend
and you're using the crossovers, it is
essentially a moving average very very
complicated. There's a little bit more
to it. I've used it out for a bit. It's
not good in Forex. I'll tell you that
now. It is only good in trending markets
like the Nasdaq and Bitcoin and things
like this. And again, you can just be
using something else instead such as a
moving average or uh simply price
action. So, the Ichimoku Cloud, it can
be useful in trend following situations,
uh but um it's not something that we
want to be actually using. So, it's
probably low down on the D tier here
actually, guys. Right, taking a look
there, guys. Hopefully, you remember
what everything is there. Uh that is I
think that is a great final final sum
up. I would I would essentially if you
could use just one it would be the S
tier here at the price action. If you
wanted to use two, I would say, you
know, match up some things with price
action. Two or three Fibonacci, price
action, maybe the candlestick patterns,
volume. This These These are the These
are the kings here. They can all really
go hand in hand there if you are a good
trader. If you're just a beginner, maybe
RSI moving average might be a good thing
to combine together uh because those are
really nice and easy to to kind of just
look at the the lines you're beginner.
Uh but I would say as an advanced trader
these are kind of the ones that you
really want to do. And these guys down
here, these are so worthless. Nobody
should ever use these uh pretty much.
But if you are a a kind of a kind of a
wonky type guy, you might be able to
make a strategy that works along with
those. All right, guys. If you like that
content, if you like the tier list, let
me know um some other tier list
suggestions in the comment section
below. Uh we can do this again cuz
that's kind of a fun video. I rather
like it. Um if you guys want to be a
part of signal group or um education or
anything, link in the description.
There's also a free Discord in there as
well. Follow me on Instagram. See you
guys next time. Listen.
[Music]
All right.